<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Plugins | Freelance Projects]]></title>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/categories/plugins/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-20T22:34:07+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Upeksha Wisidagama]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress Pages Creation Plugin]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/wordpress-pages-creation-plugin/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-20T15:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/wordpress-pages-creation-plugin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This project is different from other freelance projects in many ways. First I failed. Then I was promoted to level 16. Again I succeeded. Next I was paid. Finally I was recognized as a good service provider.</p>

<h2> Level 16 @ Freelancer.com [Novice]</h2>


<p>I was able to reach the Level 16 at Freelancer.com with the completion of this project.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/level16-novice.jpg" title="Level 16 Novice" alt="Level 16 Novice" /></p>

<h2>A Failed Project</h2>


<p>I wasn&rsquo;t able to delivery what I promised initially. The result was a bad review from the employer.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/communication-failure.jpg" title="Communication Failure" alt="Communication Failure" /></p>

<p>I deserve that review. I failed to deliver what he initially demanded to do. I thought I would be able to complete the project. But Pinterest made it hard to connect with them without a proper API. The following is the initial project description.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/wordpress-plugin-post-to-pinterest.jpg" title="WordPress Plugin Post to Pinterest" alt="WordPress Plugin Post to Pinterest" /></p>

<p>See the above review: <b>On Time: No</b></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve tried many hours to get this plugin work. All attempts failed. Project went for a long time than I initially promised. However, employer assigned me the other project he had posted on freelancer.com. I knew that I could complete that project, at the first impression of the project description. I accepted the project. I delivered it very quickly.</p>

<h2>5.50USD Tip</h2>


<p>I received a tip for the successful completion of the second project.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/5usd-bonus.jpg" title="5 USD Bonus" alt="5 USD Bonus" /></p>

<h2>Recognition as a Good Service Provider</h2>


<p>Eventhough the first project failed, the second project was a success. I tried my best to deliver a good plugin for the second project. I received a comment from the employer worth of thousands of dollars.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Thanks for the work you have done. You really do go an extra mile and that is what separates you from the a lot of people. Being a service provider always go along way. So Thanks a bunch. Have a great weekend! :&ndash;) All the best.</p></p><p><ul><br/><li>runeellingsen</p></blockquote></li>
</ul>


<p>The following are the feedbacks exchanged after the project completion.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/post-to-pinterest-feedback.jpg" title="Post to Pinterest Feedback" alt="Post to Pinterest Feedback" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
