<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: WordPress | Freelance Projects]]></title>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/categories/wordpress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-07T21:58:49+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Upeksha Wisidagama]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress Toolbar Customization]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/wordpress-toolbar-customization/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-15T20:55:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/wordpress-toolbar-customization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The project poster (Mr. Cstoudt) wanted to add custom menu to their WordPress Admin Bar.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The correct term is ToolBar (not Admin Bar). The Toolbar was added in Version 3.1 as Admin Bar and in Version 3.3 it was replaced by the Toolbar.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The following is an screenshot of the project description posted on freelancer.com.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/wordpress-toolbar-customization-description.jpg" title="WordPress Toolbar Customization Description" alt="WordPress Toolbar Customization Description" /></p>

<p>I decided to implement administration functions of the menu with WordPress native menu editor. E.g. One can add/edit menu items as though it is an ordinary WordPress menu. But this menu will be displayed on WordPress Toolbar.</p>

<h2>A Hidden Challenge</h2>


<p>A challenge was hidden in this project. Menu items were dependent of the membership level being visited. i.e. different menu needs to be displayed for different membership levels. Membership management was done by another plugin. I was able to successfully satisfy these requirements too.</p>

<p>I was able to hook into the proper point of WordPress execution and inject the new menu to WordPress Toolbar. I was able to complete the project successfully.</p>

<p>The following is the review by cstoudt for the correct interpretation and implementation of his needs for this project.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/wp-toolbar-customization-feedback.jpg" title="WordPress Toolbar Customization Feedback" alt="WordPress Toolbar Customization Feedback" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Language Parlor Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/language-parlor-project/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T21:35:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/language-parlor-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Language Parlor website allows you to learn new languages. It is designed to offer many language courses in many levels. This project is from nit3hawks.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/language-parlor-project-description.jpg" title="Language Parlor Project Description" alt="Language Parlor Project Description" /></p>

<p>Paid subscribers are allowed to watch premium learning videos. Multiple logins using the same password was prevented. This website was based on a premium theme called &lsquo;clarity&rsquo;.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/language-parlor-project-banner.png" title="Language Parlor Project Banner" alt="Language Parlor Project Banner" /></p>

<p>This website connects to PayPal to process the subscription. I used &lsquo;PayPal Framework&rsquo; plugin for this project. After successful completion I earned $330USD(including $30USD bonus).</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/language-parlor-project-feedback.jpg" title="Language Parlor Project Feedback" alt="Language Parlor Project Feedback" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coming Soon Site Using WordPress CMS]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/coming-soon-site/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/coming-soon-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A coming soon website was built for an &lsquo;Online Tennis Ladder Site&rsquo; called EXP Tennis. This was built using popular &lsquo;WordPress Content Management System&rsquo;. I developed the WordPress Theme from the HTML template given by the client. His name on freelancer.com was &lsquo;nit3hawkz&rsquo;.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/coming-soon-site-project-description.jpg" title="Coming Soon Site Project Description" alt="Coming Soon Site Project Description" /></p>

<h2>First Project on Freelancer.com</h2>


<p>This was my first project in Freelancer.com. There were a total of 31 freelancers bidding on this project and the average bid was $408USD. I was fortunate enough to win the bid and get selected as the winning bidder for this &lsquo;Coming Soon Site&rsquo;.</p>

<p>Nit3hawkz was the project poster. He already had some other projects on freelancer.com. The main site related to this coming soon site, i.e. the actual coming soon site was already being developed, at the time I was awarded the project.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/coming-soon-site-screenshot.jpg" title="Coming Soon Site Screenshot" alt="Coming Soon Site Screenshot" /></p>

<p>The project was completed successfully and I received a 5 star rating for the project.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/coming-soon-site-feedback.jpg" title="Coming Soon Site Feedback" alt="Coming Soon Site Feedback" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
