<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Finance | Freelance Projects]]></title>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/categories/finance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-17T18:06:03+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Upeksha Wisidagama]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I earned A Dollar]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/how-i-earned-one-usd/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-01T11:05:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/how-i-earned-one-usd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I only needed one dollar. If you&rsquo;ve missed that post, <a href="/blog/i-only-need-one-dollar/" >read it here</a>.</p>

<p>However, I was fortunate enough to receive a dollar. In fact, I received 10 USD. Mr. Cstoudt released 10 previously milestoned dollars.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/how-i-earned-one-dollar.jpg" title="How I earned one dollar" alt="How I earned one dollar" /></p>

<h2>An Unreleased Milestone</h2>


<p>Do you remember once I completed a project for Mr. Cstoudt? (See: <a href="/blog/wordpress-toolbar-customization/" >WordPress Toolbar Customization</a>) Eventhough I completed that project successfully, there remained an unreleased and fogotten milestone. While I was thinking how to find the missing dollar yesterday, while I was browsing through my freelancer.com financial dashboard, I noticed this milestone. I contacted Mr. Cstoudt and asked him to release the milestone.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/requesting-to-release-the-milestone.jpg" title="Requesting to release the milestone" alt="Requesting to release the milestone" /></p>

<p>I received this about 8:10 on 1st July, 2013. This is a new month. I was finding a dollar in the previous month. However I decided this payment should be counted as received in the previous month. I live in Sri Lanka (+5.30UTC). Client sent the payment from USA (-6.00UTC). For Mr. Cstoudt it was only 20:40 on 30th June, 2013. See the below illustration.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/sri-lanka-usa-time-relationship.jpg" title="Sri Lanka USA Time Relationship" alt="Sri Lanka USA Time Relationship" /></p>

<h2>Finally, I collected the missing dollar</h2>


<p>Just before the end of the month (somewhere +X.YYUTC), I was able to withdraw money from my freelancer.com account. Thanks Mr. Cstout (10 USD) and Mr. Brant (30 USD).</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/32-usd-to-sri-lanka.jpg" title="32 USD to Sri Lanka" alt="32 USD to Sri Lanka" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I only need One Dollar]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/i-only-need-one-dollar/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-30T09:13:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/i-only-need-one-dollar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is the last day of this month (June, 2013). My account balance is &lsquo;29.19&rsquo;.</p>

<p>In order to withdraw money from freelancer.com, My account balance should be at least 30 USD.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/i-only-need-one-dollar.jpg" title="I only need one dollar" alt="I only need one dollar" /></p>

<p>I recently completed a project for Mr. Brant (Two WordPress Customizations). I agreed with him to be paid 30 USD for the completion of this project. But freelancer.com charged me a fee of 5 USD. ( Freelancer.com service fee is fair compared to other service providers. But at this time the total went below 30 USD ).</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/wordpress-freelancer-cost.jpg" title="WordPress Freelancer Cost" alt="WordPress Freelancer Cost" /></p>

<p>So I started bidding on projects, planing to earn the missing 1 USD. Today is the final day of the month. Still, I haven&rsquo;t had a chance to win a project. I started to lower my bids. Then people started to ask me why my bid is so low (they can&rsquo;t trust that the work could be that cheap). See the below conversation with one of my potential clients (Alias: MasterCook).</p>

<p><blockquote><p>MasterCook: ok so 1. why you bid so low and how do i know your not wasting my time</p></p><p><p>Upeksha: I have been bidding for a couple of days without any work. I have $29 in my account and I need at least another $1 to withdraw money from freelancer.com.</p></p><p><p>Upeksha: I have done various WordPress related projects. I am confident I can do the customizations you need.</p></p><p><p>MasterCook: you price is good but I am worried about cheap labour</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Usually, freelancer.com charges 10% of the total project price (for a 30USD project that should be 3USD). At this time they charged 5 USD. The reason is the lowest project commission is 5 USD. However now I can&rsquo;t withdraw funds to Skrill account without another dollar. I only need One Dollar.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/blog/cannot-withdraw-less-than-30-usd.jpg" title="Cannot withdraw less than 30 USD" alt="Cannot withdraw less than 30 USD" /></p>

<h2>Update 2013-07-01</h2>


<p>I was able to receive the missing dollar. Read <a href="/blog/how-i-earned-one-usd/" >how I found a dollar</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
