<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Buddhism | Freelance Projects]]></title>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/categories/buddhism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-21T14:00:59+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Upeksha Wisidagama]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nikini Full Moon Poya Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/nikini-full-moon-poya-day/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-20T18:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/nikini-full-moon-poya-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The Premise | Four Noble Truths</h2>


<p>The basic truths about the world, which Buddhists assume to be true.
(later, they completely realize that they are actually true)</p>

<p>1 &ndash; The truth of dukkha (suffering, anxiety, dissatisfaction)<br />
2 &ndash; The truth of the origin of dukkha<br />
3 &ndash; The truth of the cessation of dukkha<br />
4 &ndash; The truth of the path leading to the cessation of dukkha<br /></p>

<p>Only human beings can reason these truths are related to the reality. Beings in other worlds might
have difficulties in reasoning or even believing the above four as truth.</p>

<p>Read More: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Noble_Truths">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Noble_Truths</a></p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/nikini/thinker.jpg" title="Thinker" alt="Thinker" /></p>

<h2>The Argument | Interdependent Co-Arising</h2>


<p>Buddhist argument is based on and flow from the above basic truths and valid for all rational beings who understand logic in all possible worlds (not just for human beings in
the sensual realm).</p>

<p>This argument is valid and any intelligent person, if he
can reason logically because he practiced it, will accept the argument as a valid argument.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>When this is, that is.<br/>From the arising of this comes the arising of that.<br/>When this isn&rsquo;t, that isn&rsquo;t.<br/>From the cessation of this comes the cessation of that.</p></p><p><p>Translator: Thanissaro Bikkhu</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The argument about dependent origin may seem unsound to the people who don&rsquo;t understand or don&rsquo;t accept the four basic truths.</p>

<p>1 -With Ignorance as condition, Mental Formations arise (With Avidyā as condition, Saṃskāra arises)<br /><br />
2 -With Mental Formations as condition, Consciousness arises (With Saṃskāra as condition, Vijñāna arises)<br /><br />
3 -With Consciousness as condition, Mind and Matter arise (With Vijñāna as condition, Nāmarūpa arises)<br /><br />
4 -With Mind and Matter as condition, Sense Gates arise (With Nāmarūpa as condition, Ṣaḍāyatana arises)<br /><br />
5 -With Sense Gates as condition, Contact arises (With Ṣaḍāyatana as condition, Sparśa arises)<br /><br />
6 -With Contact as condition, Feeling arises (With Sparśa as condition, Vedanā arises)<br /><br />
7 -With Feeling as condition, Craving arises (With Vedanā as condition, Tṛṣṇā arises)<br /><br />
8 -With Craving as condition, Clinging arises (With Tṛṣṇā as condition, Upādāna arises)<br /><br />
9 -With Clinging as condition, Becoming arises (With Upādāna as condition, Bhava arises)<br /><br />
10 -With Becoming as a condition, Birth arises (With Bhava as condition, Jāti arises)<br /><br />
11 -With Birth as condition, Aging and Dying arise (With Jāti as condition, Jarāmaraṇa arises)<br /></p>

<p>Read More: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prat%C4%ABtyasamutp%C4%81da">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prat%C4%ABtyasamutp%C4%81da</a></p>

<h2>The Destination | Nibbana</h2>


<p>The final destination where Noble Eightfold Path will lead you to. Spiritually, the
perfect state of being. I always try to visualize the peace and tranquility I will
experience after reaching this state.</p>

<p>Read More: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nirvana">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nirvana</a></p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/nikini/nirvana.jpg" title="Tranquility" alt="Tranquility" /></p>

<h2>The Path | Noble EightFold Path</h2>


<p>The path taught by the greatest pragmatic teacher. The Perfect Path.</p>

<p>Wisdom</p>

<p>1 &ndash; Right view<br />
2 &ndash; Right intention<br /></p>

<p>Ethical conduct</p>

<p>3 &ndash; Right speech<br />
4 &ndash; Right action<br />
5 &ndash; Right livelihood<br /></p>

<p>Concentration</p>

<p>6 &ndash; Right effort<br />
7 &ndash; Right mindfulness<br />
8 &ndash; Right concentration<br /></p>

<p>Read More: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path</a></p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/nikini/the_thinker.jpg" title="The Thinker" alt="The Thinker" /></p>

<p>The Thinker: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thinker">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thinker</a></p>

<h2>Appendix A | Contemporary Ethical Philosophy</h2>


<p>Derek Parfit is a moral philosopher, who once described an state of mind where it is nealy close that of a practising Buddhist.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/nikini/derek-parfit.jpg" title="Derek Parfit" alt="Derek Parfit" /></p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ldquo;My life seemed like a glass tunnel, through which I was moving faster every<br/>year, and at the end of which there was darkness&hellip; [However] When I changed my view, the walls of my glass tunnel disappeared. I now live in the open air.<br/>There is still a difference between my life and the lives of other people. But<br/>the difference is less. Other people are closer. I am less concerned about the<br/>rest of my own life, and more concerned about the lives of others.&rdquo;</p></p><p><ul><br/><li>Derek Parfit</p></blockquote></li>
</ul>


<p>Derek Parfits &lsquo;Reasons and Persons&rsquo; (described by Alan Ryan as &ldquo;something close to a work of genius&rdquo;) was published in 1984. His second
major work(&lsquo;On What Matters&rsquo;) is also available on Amazon. I added both these books to my
wish list, wishing to read someday. (I give priority to other books in my wish list.
They must be read first.)</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/nikini/on-what-matters.jpg" title="On What Matters" alt="On What Matters" /></p>

<p>See More: <a href="http://onwhatmatters.tumblr.com/">http://onwhatmatters.tumblr.com/</a></p>

<h2>Appendix B | Money</h2>


<p>Science is science. Politics is politics. Art is art. Economics is economics.
Sport is sport. Psychology is psychology. Medicine is medicine. Engineering is
engineering. Marketing is marketing. Business is business. Technology is technology.</p>

<p>Buddhism is Buddhism. Buddhism is necessary, but not sufficient.</p>

<p>When you are hungry, you can&rsquo;t eat ethics. So make sure you make enough money
to buy foods and maintain your moral standards.</p>

<p>(Currently, the distribution is NOT according to the moral value. Needs more reading on Economics?)</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/nikini/hunger.jpg" title="Hunger" alt="Hunger" /></p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ldquo;We are the animals that can both understand and respond to reasons. These abilities have given us great knowledge, and power to control the future of life on Earth. Though there may be life elsewhere, there may be no other animals like us. We may be the only rational beings in the Universe.&rdquo;</p></p><p><p>&mdash; Derek Parfit<br/>&mdash; On What Matters Volume One (June 20, 2011)<br/>+ Part One: Reasons<br/>+ Chapter One: Normative Concepts<br/>+ Section One: Sufficient and Decisive Reasons<br/>+ Page: 60<br/>+ The above is the opening sentence of the first paragraph.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asala Full Moon Poya Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/asala-full-moon-poya-day/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-22T17:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/asala-full-moon-poya-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The First Disclosure - The Wheel of Truth</h2>


<p>Today is Asala Full Moon Poya Day. It was on the Esala Poya Day, seven weeks after the attainment of Buddhahood, the Buddha delivered His first discourse, the Dhammachakkapavattna Sutta (the wheel of truth) to the five Ascetics, Kondanna, Vappa, Bhaddiya, Mahanama and Assaji at Isipathanaya in Benares (Baranasi).</p>

<p>The sermon consisted of the central teachings of the Buddha &ndash; the Four Noble Truths and the Noble Eightfold Path. At the end of the Sutta the eldest Kondangna Thera attained sotapatti, the first stage of sainthood.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ldquo;What, O Bhikkus, is that middle path the Thathagatha has discovered which promotes sight, knowledge, peace, higher wisdom, Enlightenment and Nibbana? It is this Noble Eightfold Path&rdquo;.</p></p><p><p>-Buddha</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Read more on Noble Eightfold Path: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path</a></p>

<h2>Society and Values</h2>


<p>Values: In a society, we have values. Values allow us to work as community and improve further. Individuals have values themselves. Groups and societies share common values.</p>

<p>Example of a Value: Treating parents in their Elderhood.</p>

<p>Upon birth humans are one of the most vulnerable animals to external threats. Parents protects us from the external and feed us. They gave us education and other required things for our life. This is a good behavior. How do we reinforce this pattern? Parents should be rewarded for what they are doing. Looking at the current generation, next generation of parents will treat their children even better. By retaining this value in our group or society, we&rsquo;ll be able to develop our societies better and faster.</p>

<p>Another Example of a Value: Respecting our teachers.</p>

<p>Teachers are paid for their service. Do we need to respect them or worship them? Well, according to Abraham Maslow, Money isn&rsquo;t enough. We all have self-esteem needs. By helping teachers to satisfy their self-esteem needs, we can make sure the next generation of teachers teach their children even better. Yes, one can argue, society should pay more for teachers so that they can purchase self-esteem. I agree, that&rsquo;s possible. But that leads to another side effect which I don&rsquo;t need to discuss in this article.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/asala/maslows-hierarchy-of-needs.png" title="Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs" alt="Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs" /></p>

<p>Read More: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ldquo;the study of crippled, stunted, immature, and unhealthy specimens can yield only a cripple psychology and a cripple philosophy.&rdquo;</p></p><p><ul><br/><li>Abraham Maslow</li><br/></ul></p><p><br/><p>(Maslow studied the healthiest 1% of the college student population)</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Read More: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_Maslow">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_Maslow</a></p>

<p>Now we understand how the values aid the development of a society and how we can make the development faster by carefully choosing what our values should be.</p>

<h2>Religion as a Medium of Communication</h2>


<p>Values are concepts, more specifically abstract concepts. We can use values within ourselves but cannot communicate. We need symbols to represent values.</p>

<p>Values and Symbols: In binary digital electronics, binary means we have only two values i.e. being or not-being. Digital means we map numbers into these two values. 1 as being and 0 as not-being. Now how do we communicate this? We have the utility of electronics. We symbolize a voltage difference of 5V as 1 or being. Otherwise 0 or not-being.</p>

<p>We use voltage level to symbolize binary digital value. We can communicate digital values through Voltage Symbols. The critical point to understand is a random variation of voltage across a conducting medium is of no use. The value lies within the symbols and only the society that encodes the value into a symbol can decode it.</p>

<p>Religions can be thought as a set of symbols that communicate values across the time and generation aiding societies to increase their rate of development.</p>

<h2>Religious Professionals</h2>


<p><img class='center' src="/images/asala/Jesus_and_the_doctors_of_the_Faith.jpg" title="Jesus and the doctors of the Faith" alt="Jesus and the doctors of the Faith" />
Jesus and the doctors of the Faith, a painting by a follower of Giuseppe Ribera.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Professions tend to be autonomous, which means they have a high degree of control of their own affairs: &ldquo;professionals are autonomous insofar as they can make independent judgments about their work&rdquo;. This usually means &ldquo;the freedom to exercise their professional judgment.&rdquo;</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Read more: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profession">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profession</a></p>

<p>Religious leaders in the society should maintain a professional status. In fact, they are more important than other professionals such as medical doctors, accountants, teachers, engineers, etc.</p>

<h2>Philosophical Independence</h2>


<p>In a complex world or society, it&rsquo;s hard to be philosophically independent, even if you have high intellectual capacity. The best option is to choose someone good to depend on. I chose Gauthama Buddha as my teacher of life. I happy shaping my life according to Buddhism.</p>

<p>Please allocate some of your precious time for religious and spiritual activities.</p>

<h2>Wheel of Life</h2>


<p><img class='center' src="/images/asala/dharma-wheel.png" title="Dharma Wheel" alt="Dharma Wheel" /></p>

<p>In Buddhism, according to the Pali Canon (Vinayapitaka, Khandhaka, Mahavagga, and Dhammacakkappavattanasutta), eight spokes represent the Noble Eightfold Path.</p>

<p>Read More: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noble_Eightfold_Path</a></p>

<p>I am practicing Noble Eightfold Path as the way leading to the cessation of suffering (dukkha) and the achievement of self-awakening.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spiritual Life - The Ultimate Teacher]]></title>
    <link href="http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/the-great-teacher/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T22:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://uw-freelancer.github.io/blog/the-great-teacher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class='center' src="/images/buddhism/lord-buddha-gal-viharaya.jpg" title="Lord Buddha - Gal Viharaya" alt="Lord Buddha - Gal Viharaya" /></p>

<p>Teachers help us to learn. Of course we can learn from books, Internet, etc. But behind them, there are people. They too belong to the teachers set. You can become a teacher too. There are special set of teachers who teach the most advanced lessons of life. Their teachings are timeless. Most of major religious leaders belong to this set. I myself consider &lsquo;Lord Buddha&rsquo; as the ultimate teacher. I respect all other religious leaders too.</p>

<p>I can write the names of other religions and terms related to them, but honestly I haven&rsquo;t had enough time to study them. By writing them in the wrong order or in the wrong context, I will not do any justice to them. I believe, most of them must be great, but within my knowledge and experience, I accept &lsquo;Lord Buddha&rsquo; is the greatest teacher in our world.</p>

<h2>Mental Health</h2>


<p>Mental health is an important aspect of an individual. One must be mentally healthy in order to function well in this world. The following are some of the personality disorders.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Obsessive–compulsive personality disorder (OCPD) is a personality disorder characterized by a pervasive pattern of preoccupation with orderliness, perfectionism, mental and interpersonal control at the expense of flexibility, openness, and efficiency.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Obsessive%E2%80%93compulsive_personality_disorder" >OCPD</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Borderline personality disorder (BPD) is a personality disorder whose essential features are a pattern of marked impulsivity and instability of affects, interpersonal relationships, and self image.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Borderline_personality_disorder" >BPD</a></p>

<p>The above two conditions are meant to remind you of various disorders that can make you mentally unhealthy.</p>

<h2>Insanity</h2>


<p>Insanity, craziness or madness is a spectrum of behaviors characterized by certain abnormal mental or behavioral patterns. Insanity may manifest as violations of societal norms, including a person becoming a danger to themselves or others. (Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insanity" >Insanity</a>).</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/buddhism/insane-asylum-brentwood.jpg" title="Insane Asylum Brentwood" alt="Insane Asylum Brentwood" /></p>

<p>Meaning of Life, After Life, etc. are the areas of curiosity that you can&rsquo;t completely understand. If you think more about them without understanding what you are doing it can lead to undesirable mental effects.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t make your decisions based on purely natural scientific knowledge and methodologies. Social science has their own body of knowledge making our world a better place. Despite of being true, some concepts are meant to remain in the society. (not all of us are intellectuals or philosophers)</p>

<p>I have met some people, who faced a major setback in their life. They were unable to recover to their normal lives. They ended up in mental hospitals.</p>

<h2>Causes</h2>


<p>You need to identity your unhealthy thinking patterns in order to reduce the risk of being caught in a mental disorder. If you regularly feel some unease you should consult a psychiatrist.</p>

<h2>Active Externalization</h2>


<p>You can write your views on a paper or publish it online. Then you no longer need to carry them in your head.</p>

<p>This technique is called &lsquo;Active Externalization&rsquo;. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Externalization" >Externalization</a></p>

<h2>Open Source</h2>


<p>By publishing your views where others can read, you make the source open. Others can criticize your views. You can rethink about your own views according to others advices.</p>

<p>This enables you to analyze your own thoughts against others views. You can even exercise &lsquo;Double Dissociation&rsquo;. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissociation_(psychology)" >Dissociation</a></p>

<h2>Meaning of Life</h2>


<p><img class='center' src="/images/buddhism/where-do-we-come-from.jpg" title="Where Do We Come From" alt="Where Do We Come From" /></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The three women with a child represent the beginning of life; the middle group symbolizes the daily existence of young adulthood; and in the final group, according to the artist, &ldquo;an old woman approaching death appears reconciled and resigned to her thoughts&rdquo;; at her feet, &ldquo;a strange white bird&hellip;represents the futility of words.&rdquo; The blue idol in the background apparently represents what Gauguin described as &ldquo;the Beyond.&rdquo; Of its entirety he said, &ldquo;I believe that this canvas not only surpasses all my preceding ones, but that I shall never do anything better—or even like it.&rdquo; In fact, after completing this painting, Gauguin felt so convinced that the rest of his life would be unsuccessful that he attempted suicide unsuccessfully. Artist: Paul Gauguin</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Read More: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meaning_of_life" >Meaning of Life</a></p>

<h2>Uncertainty</h2>


<p>People talk about &lsquo;Living in an uncertain world&rsquo; and about &lsquo;suspending the judgment&rsquo;. Read about them. Try to understand them. So you can make an informed decision on what you are going to believe and how you are going to live in this world.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/buddhism/bertrand-russell.jpg" title="Burtrand Russell" alt="Burtrand Russell" /></p>

<h2>Immanuel Kant on Enlightenment</h2>


<p><blockquote><p>Enlightenment is man’s emergence from his self-imposed nonage. Nonage is the inability to use one’s own understanding without another’s guidance. This nonage is self-imposed if its cause lies not in lack of understanding but in indecision and lack of courage to use one’s own mind without another’s guidance. &ndash; Immanuel Kant</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I like this essay. Source: <a href="/blog/what-is-enlightenment/" >What is Enlightenment</a>.</p>

<h2>Buddhist Philosophy</h2>


<p>Personally, I believe in an afterlife and the previous lives. I run a process inside my brain which loads Buddhist Concepts into my mind so that I can use them easily to perceive the world in a Buddhist way. I believe in &lsquo;Karma&rsquo; too. What we have now is the result of what we did in the past. (Actually these concepts are not as simple as the previous sentence)</p>

<p>Source: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethics" >Ethics</a></p>

<h2>Four Noble Truths</h2>


<p><blockquote><p>Normally we think our happiness is contingent upon external circumstances and situations, rather than upon our own inner attitude toward things, or toward life in general. The Buddha was saying that dissatisfaction is part of life, even if we are seeking happiness and even if we manage to find temporary happiness. The very fact that it is temporary means that sooner or later the happiness is going to pass. So the Buddha said that unless we understand this and see how pervasive dissatisfaction or duhkha is, it is impossible for us to start looking for real happiness. &ndash; Traleg Kyabgon Rinpoche</p></blockquote></p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Noble_Truths">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Noble_Truths</a></p>

<h2>Money</h2>


<p>We need to earn money to live a successful life. You need to face the competition. You have to have sufficient amount of money to live a noble and spiritual life. Without money, one will be working hard just for food.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/buddhism/5000-rupees.jpg" title="5000 Rupees" alt="5000 Rupees" /></p>

<p>Lord Buddha teaches us how to balance our mundane and spiritual lives for a greater life. Lord Buddha is the ultimate teacher of life.</p>

<h2>Further Reading</h2>


<p>Lord Buddha is the greatest teacher. Read more about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gautama_Buddha" >Lord Buddha</a>.</p>

<p><img class='center' src="/images/buddhism/sandakada-pahana.jpg" title="Sandakada Pahana" alt="Sandakada Pahana" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
